mapr.com 2017-02-09

# Privacy Policy | MapR

#### General Information

MapR Technologies respects the privacy of our customers, business partners, and other visitors to our websites who may provide personal information or data to us, and we recognize the need for appropriate protections and management of such personal information and data. 

#### Scope

This Privacy Statement applies to information and data collected by MapR through its products or services and website(s) (located at: [http://www.mapr.com](http://www.mapr.com/)). This Statement covers how MapR treats information about you that MapR collects and receives, including information related to your use of MapR products and services.

#### Information MapR Collects

**Personal Information.** You may provide Personal Information to us when you visit the MapR Websites, join the MapR community, sign-up for one of our mailing lists, request news and product information, complete surveys, email us or purchase, download or install MapR products and services. _“Personal Information”_ is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, phone number, employer, job title or resume.

MapR does not sell or rent your personal information to anyone. We may only release personal information when we believe that it is required to comply with the law, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of MapR, our users, or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for purposes of fraud protection and credit risk management. Please note, MapR mailing lists may be archived by several third party sites and your email address may be found on these archive sites. MapR doesn't have control over mailing list archive sites.

**Automatically Collected Information.** MapR collects tracking or usage data when users visit the MapR Websites, open one of our HTML emails, (including page views, traffic flows, search terms, click throughs, Internet Protocol address, web browser type, websites visited before or after the MapR Websites and dates and times of your visits), or download or install MapR products or services (including install status (success/error), installer id, license level, services installed, cluster id, number of nodes installed).

**Cookies.** As part of our approach to providing personalized services on the MapR Websites, MapR uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small data file sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your hard drive. The cookie remains even after you close your browser and allows easier access the next time the same page is visited. For example, a cookie is sent when you sign-up or login to the MapR Websites. With your consent, cookies can store Personal Information from forms you fill out to create a user profile so that you do not have to re-enter the information each time you visit. 

If you do not want your Personal Information to be stored by cookies, you can configure your browser so that it notifies you whenever a cookie is received. This way you can decide each time to accept cookies or not. However, the use of cookies may be necessary to receive certain features on the MapR Websites and choosing to reject cookies may reduce the functionality of the MapR Websites. Your browser should include precise instructions explaining how to disable or control the acceptance of cookies.

#### How MapR Uses or Discloses Information

MapR uses the information that we collect to provide to you all of the features and services found on the MapR Websites, products and services, to create new features and functionality and to improve the way the MapR Websites, products and services work and look, and for diagnostics.

**Personal Information.** MapR may use your email address or other Personal Information: (a) without further consent, for non-promotional or administrative purposes such as notifying you of major site updates, and (b) to send promotional related communications to you unless you opt-out of receiving such communications. MapR does not sell or rent your Personal Information to anyone. We may release Personal Information when we believe that it is required to comply with the law, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of MapR, our users, or others or if you request that we release such information. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for purposes of fraud protection and credit risk management. 

MapR may disclose both Personal Information and automatically collected information to third party businesses, organizations or persons to process such information on our behalf, to provide website maintenance and security, to offer certain features on the MapR Websites, to assist us in improving the way the MapR Websites, products and services work and look, and/or to create new features. Please note, MapR mailing lists may be archived by several third party sites and your email address may be found on these archive sites. MapR doesn't have control over mailing list archive sites. 

**Automatically Collected Information and Cookies.** We use automatically collected information to monitor aggregate usage metrics, trends and preferences and to improve the MapR Websites, products and services. We may also share this anonymous traffic and demographic information in aggregate form with advertisers and other business partners. We may share automatically collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, products, and/or functionality on the MapR Websites. We may use automatically collected information and cookies information to remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the MapR Website.

#### Notification of Changes

If we change our Privacy Statement, we will post an updated privacy policy at www.mapr.com/privacy. If we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users via email. Users will be able to opt out of any new use of their Personal Information. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to stay informed about how we are protecting the Personal Information we collect. Your continued use of the MapR Websites constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Statement and any updates.

#### User Profile and Password

You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any unique password and profile information at all times.

#### Choice/Opt-Out.

The MapR Websites, products and services provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and from our partners any time we collect Personal Information.

#### In the Event of a Merger or Sale

If MapR should have its assets sold to or merge with another entity, information MapR receives from you through the MapR Websites is a MapR asset and may be transferred.

#### Special Note to International Users

The MapR Websites are hosted in the United States. If you are a user accessing the MapR Wesites from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from United States laws, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States which does not have the same data protection laws as the EU and other regions and by providing your personal data you consent to:

  * the use of your personal data for the uses identified above in accordance with the Privacy Statement; and
  * the transfer of your personal data to the United States as indicated above.

#### Contact MapR

If you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Statement or the practices of MapR, you can [contact us](mailto:info@mapr.com).

Last updated: May 8, 2015
